hi this video is going to go over the
American hip thrust so basically I um
the hip thrust variation that I U came
up with and that I always employed you
hinged from right here you know and you
came up from right here this is where
you hinge but one day I was watching
Timothy Ferris do a hip brust and he
would get the bar into position like
this and do them from here and uh I had
never tried that way it's a lot
different um I actually the first time I
tried it my glutes cramped up so bad um
and I've always wondered which variation
produces higher EMG and it's the
American hip thrust so I think this is
the highest you can possibly get your
glute activation up is through this
exercise here but here's how you do it
and remember this bench is 16 in high
this is good for me some benches are too
high if they're 18 to 23 that's way way
too high for most people in general 14
to 16 some some people even you prefer
smaller boxes so make sure your bench
isn't too high and that it's stable see
how I have it up against this wooden uh
wooden Dow which is supported against
the rack so the bench can't slide back
all right I got the barbell I roll it
into place if you're not strong enough
to use 45 lb plates that's a problem
because you won't be able to roll it
over the top
in that situation bumper plates work
well cuz 25 and 35 lb plates and even 10
lb plates are the same size as these 45s
but most gyms don't have bumper plates
so if that's the case you kind of got to
like pick it up like deadlift it sit
down on the bench and then go back down
or have someone else help you place it
on your hips um the last thing is I'm
lucky the bar sits right above my pelvis
and on my hip
flexors um it doesn't it's it's resting
on muscle some people aren't built that
way their bones stick out more and they
can't do that they need padding an ax
balance pad or a handed thick bar pad
works best here but I don't need it so I
roll it into place I get into position
here now watch what I do with my elbows
now one thing this has to be centered
perfectly if this bar is not centered it
won't work so see how I use these lines
to tell that this is centered right over
my hips okay I get into position
I'm way up
high and now from here I climb up to
right here now watch my pelvic action
here I'm in anterior tilt I come up
posterior tilt anterior tilt posterior
see this it's not just if extension see
my abdominals they actually shorten as I
come up
oh those get the glutes
burning sometimes people find that
they're weaker at this variation some
people find that they're stronger I
happen to be a little bit stronger this
way but this doesn't replace the
standard barbell hip thrust there's lots
of good variations of
bridging I like to do the standard
barbell hip thrust the barbell glute
Bridge the American hip thrust and the
single I get drust they all um they're
synergistic with one another so those
are my four favorite variations that you
should be doing so give this give this a
try see if you can get the right feel
try and get some pelvic action into it
not just hip extension but some
posterior pelvic tilt as well